

# Neil Mackay

UI/UX Designer HTML/CSS Frontend Developer

## **LOCATION**

Cape Town / Remote

## **PORTFOLIO**

Neil Mackay portfolio

# CONTACT



neilmackay01@gmail.com



+1 401 855 9078 +27 74 877 2604



@neilmackay



dribbble.com/neilmackay



## **PROFILE**

I bring strong problem-solving, troubleshooting and analytical skills that have shown to improve websites for various clients and my creative approach to frontend web development has yielded positive feedback from both users and clients of websites I have worked on.



## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **UI Designer and HTML & CSS Developer - YAS**

10/2019 - Current

- Delivered and designed visually compelling web designs with user-friendly UI that is cross-browser compatible and mobile responsive.
- Weekly meetings on Google Hangouts with the owner and back-end developer.
  Daily updates through Trello.
- Wrote the front-end HTML and CSS for created page designs using Bootstrap 4.
- · Collaborated with the back-end developers on GitHub.

#### **HTML & CSS Developer - Freelance**

09/2019 - Current

- · Writing of HTML and CSS code to create webpages of the design mockups.
- Fixing of layout issues.
- Testing of web pages for cross-browser compatibility.
- Work closely with the owner to ensure the development of the received design is to the correct standard.

#### **Business Owner**

06/2018 - Current

- Branding and package design, which includes the design of the labels, boxes, business cards, promotional content and products.
- Designed the website using UI/UX practices focusing on layouts, buttons, typography, colours and a responsive design using Sketch.

### Front End Designer Intern - The School Bell

08/2019 - 01/2020

- Worked closely with the CEO & CMO doing weekly check-ins on Google Hangouts as well as continuous communications through email.
- Designed with the focus on guiding the user to the CTA's and improved the overall consistency of the layout.
- · Researched and implemented SEO improvements.



# **EDUCATION**

#### Free Code Camp

2019

· Studied HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

#### edX - W3Cx's Front-End Web Developer courses

2019

· Learnt how to develop web sites using the latest web standards.

#### Coursera - Graphic design, UI design, UX design

2020

Reinforced my knowledge on UI/UX design as well as graphic design.



# **SKILLS**

- · Proficient in UI/UX design skills using Sketch, Figma and Zeplin.
- Skilled in frontend web development using HTML and CSS in Visual Studio Code to create websites through Bootstrap, Wix, Shopify and other platforms. Basic knowledge of Javascript.
- Entrepreneurial background and experience in remote work using programs such as Trello, Google Hangouts.